Cristina Laura Beniczky Botta

Nationality: German, Brazilian | Phone number: (+49) 15209015869 (Mobile) | Email address: crisbotta@proton.me

Website: https://crisbotta.netlify.app/ | Address: Europa-Allee 116, 51379, Leverkusen, Germany (Home)

ABOUT ME

I have ten years experience working with diverse communities in digital literacy and STEAM in informal education, using almost exclusively free and open source software. I am also interested in the use of technology in education, digital artifacts preservation and archiving, and software and video games studies and history. Furthermore I continue brushing up my design skills and keeping up with trends in design, UI and UX. In my free time I like building LEGO, drawing and painting, hiking, playing strategy video games, baking, and reading non-fiction from areas completely unrelated to my research. I also make small contributions to some open-source software projects, but want to increase that in the future.

WORK EXPERIENCE

01/01/2005 - CURRENT

GRAPHIC DESIGNER / CONSULTANT SELF-EMPLOYED

- Logos, flyers, image treatment, illustration, layout, webdesign.
- Advising/teaching on matters related to open source software, Linux, digital literacy, and digital privacy and security.

05/2012 - 06/2022 São Paulo, Brazil

ARTS AND TECHNOLOGY EDUCATOR SESC SP SERVIÇO SOCIAL DO COMÉRCIO

- Elaborate and teach workshops, activities, and courses on subjects related to arts, culture, technology, and digital literacy for all age groups.
- Promote social inclusion and a meaningful and critical appropriation of the use of technology.
- Write texts for use in the dissemination of activities and for the SESC website.
- Create materials for online activities, including text, photography and graphics, and editing and narrating videos.
- Research and curate activities, working with invited artists, teachers, and specialists to adapt them taking into consideration the institution's and the public's needs.
- Work in collaboration with other teams at SESC in areas such as social development, after school programs, youth group, music, tourism, sports, literature.
- Research open source software and hardware for use in education, digital literacy, digital fabrication, graphic arts, and science.
- Research trends in art, media, technology and digital culture.
- Decide which new equipment and materials would be needed and acquired.

Website https://www.sescsp.org.br/

Link https://www.nytimes.com/2012/03/27/arts/brazils-leading-arts-financing-group-shares-the-wealth.html

04/2009 - 10/2009 Bremen, Germany

JUNIOR CONSULTANT IN2 - AI-POWERED WEB SOLUTIONS

- Provide analysis and feedback of user requirements.
- Contribute to the creation of business, dissemination and communication plans.
- Design logos and prepare presentation materials.

Website https://in-two.com/

06/2008 - 12/2008 Stuttgart, Germany

JUNIOR DESIGNER GABLER WERBEAGENTUR GMBH

- Design of websites, logos, flyers, mascots, catalogues, and visual identity.
- Flash animations and web banners, and the HTML/CSS part of websites.

Website https://www.werbe-gabler.com/

ART ASSISTANT LUA BRANCA

- Design of logos and flyers, image treatment, illustration, layout.
- Development of Flash websites, animations and web banners.

Website http://www.lua.ag

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

2008 - 2011 Bremen, Germany

MASTER OF SCIENCE IN DIGITAL MEDIA University of Bremen / University of the Arts Bremen

- Inter-University Study Program in cooperation between the University of Bremen, University of the Arts Bremen, and Universities of Applied Sciences Bremen and Bremerhaven.
- My master project focused on game-based learning, mobile and context aware games, and interaction design.
- My master thesis focused on how some storytelling structures and the limitations of simulations affect how video games are designed and played.

Website https://digitalmedia-bremen.de/

Thesis Oh No, I'm Dead! ... Again. Death as a Crossroad Where Different Pathways in the Study of Video Games Converge.

Link https://www.academia.edu/44443054/

Oh No Im Dead Again Death as a Crossroad Where Different Pathways in the Study of Video Games Converge

2011 - 2012 São Paulo, Brazil

POSTGRADUATE DEGREE IN HIGHER EDUCATION Centro Universitário SENAC

- The course focused mostly on andragogy and adult education, but pedagogy was also discussed and used as a base for teaching techniques comparisons.
- My dissertation focused on the history, design and use of educational software and games, and on the creation and implementation of a postgraduate course to teach educational game design.

Website https://www.sp.senac.br/centrouniversitario | Field of study Education |

Thesis Electronic Games and Digital Creation Tools for Educational Use

Link https://www.academia.edu/82819656/Jogos Eletrônicos e Ferramentas de Criação para Educação

2015 - 2017 São Paulo, Brazil

BSC IN COMPUTER SCIENCE (UNFINISHED) Universidade Paulista

Completed five (of a total of eight) semesters, but was unable to finish my degree due to family reasons. I completed courses in subjects such as structured programming languages, web development, programming logic and algorithms, data structures, object-oriented programming languages, operational systems, databases, computer graphics, computer networks.

Website https://www.unip.br/ | Field of study Computer Science

2001 - 2005 São Paulo, Brazil

BACHELOR IN GRAPHIC DESIGN Centro Universitário Belas Artes de São Paulo

My graduation project focused on showing through images and design the importance of play during childhood.

Website https://www.belasartes.br/

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): **PORTUGUESE**

	UNDERSTANDING		SPEAKING		WRITING
	Listening	Reading	Spoken production Spoken interaction		
ENGLISH	C2	C2	C2	C2	C2
GERMAN	B2	B2	B2	B2	B2

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user; B1 and B2: Independent user; C1 and C2: Proficient user

DIGITAL SKILLS

Office Software

LibreOffice | Nextcloud | LyX (LaTeX) | Microsoft 365 | Microsoft PowerPoint | Microsoft Word | Microsoft Office

Graphics Software

GIMP | Inkscape | Krita | Scribus | Adobe Illustrator | Adobe Photoshop | Adobe InDesign

Video Editing Software

Kdenlive | DaVinci Resolve | Adobe Premiere

Design and Prototyping Software

Penpot | Sozi | Figma | Canva

LMS and Instructional Design

Moodle | Articulate 360 | Adobe Captivate

Programming and Web Development

HTML | CSS | WordPress | Hugo | Java, C, Python, JavaScript, GDScript (fundamental knowledge) | Godot | MIT Scratch